

Alessandro Bagnoli

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · BACKEN

Riccione (RN), Italy

□ (+39) 3391580201 | 🗷 alessandro.bagnoli4@gmail.com | 🖸 AlessandroBagnoli | 🛅 alessandro-bagnoli

"Any sufficiently advanced technology is indistinguishable from magic."

Summary.

Currently Backend Engineer at Alpian. 4+ years of experience in backend development on Java environments and frameworks, with curiosity in exploring also the infrastructural side of the solutions I work on. Interested in devising and applying better methods of solving challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools on the backend side when needed. Current personal objective is to master both Kotlin and Go.

Work Experience ___

Alpian Riccione (RN), Italy - Full remote

BACKEND ENGINEER May 2022 - Today

Member of a Scrum Team building the backend side of the first Swiss digital private bank, leveraging microservices architecture and fully embracing the cloud native approach using GCP.

- Languages and tools: Java 11, Kotlin, Go, Maven
- Frameworks: Spring Boot, Hibernate
- Databases: both relational (PostgreSQL) and non-relational (MongoDB, Google Datastore)
- Testing libs and frameworks: JUnit, Mockito, Testcontainers
- Communication: both synchronous (REST, gRPC), and asynchronous (Google Pub/Sub, ActiveMQ)
- · Versioning: Git with Github-Flow

OverIT Riccione (RN), Italy - Full remote

BACKEND SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

October 2021 - May 2022

Backend Development and maintenance of custom web applications exposing APIs consumed both from an enterprise BPM and web frontend.

- Languages and tools: Java 8, Maven, WildFly
- Frameworks: Spring Framework, Hibernate
- Databases: relational (PostgreSQL)
- Testing libs and frameworks: JUnit, Mockito
- Communication: both synchronous (REST), and asynchronous (ActiveMQ)
- Versioning: Git with Git-Flow

I-Tel Riccione (RN), Italy

BACKEND SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

August 2018 - October 2021

Design and implementation of custom projects and middlewares required for integration with external backend systems. Migration of one of the company's products from a proprietary development platform to a new modular architecture, based on well-known frameworks.

- Languages and tools: Java 8/11, Tomcat, Asterisk
- Frameworks: Spring Boot, Hibernate
- Databases: relational (PostgreSQL)
- Communication: synchronous (REST)
- · Versioning: Git, SVN

Education

Alma Mater Studiorum - Università di Bologna

Cesena (FC), Italia

MASTER'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

September 2012 - July 2018

Certifications

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

CREDENTIAL ID: EC7RD6TJEJ411W59